Sue Darby

907-746-5978 Home 907--355-3750 Cell sue@sue-a-darby.com www.sue-a-darby.com Linkedin/suedarby

Sue is a specialist at bridging the gap between business managers and IT professionals, helping everyone understand and explain requirements. Sue excels at identifying execution steps, building processes and diagrams with detailed instructions for use. Sue has over 20 years experience with computers and is looking to make a change in career path to Technical Writer or Business Analyst.

Computer Skills

- Most common office suites, operating systems and database systems including commercial suites, cloud solutions and open source options; SharePoint, Visio, Project, StarUML, Google Drive etc. Master Certified MS Office
- Many web based social media and website building solutions as well as a variety of programming languages: BASIC, Javascript, Perl, HTML & CSS

Projects

- Critical Incident Tracking & reporting
- **Habilitation Homes Database Modifications**
- Application Tracking System design & development
- CPR & First Aid Waiver Tracker design & development
- Shared Email Management
- Technical books (2) on pattern drafting (illustrated)
- Pattern articles for 4 magazines and patterns (100)
- Website development and maintenance

Subject Matter Expert

- Archiving policy & procedures
- Filing policy & procedures
- SharePoint solution development and site administrator
- "DS3" to "Harmony" Provider Conversion Database
- Residential Habilitation provider management
- Electronic document management
- Equipment maintenance

Additional samples and information is found via my Portfolio and LinkedIn profile listed above.

Education

Charter College

Alpha Beta Kappa 3.85 GPA

Bachelors of Science Degree - Business Management and Technology: Concentration in Business Applications Bachelors of Science Degree - Business Management and Technology

Associate of Applied Science Degree - Computer Science: Concentration in Business Applications

Associate of Applied Science Degree - Business Management Practice

Certificate - Computerized Office Associate

Certificate - Computerized Office Specialist

Experience

iA3.io

Webmaster & Technical Writer

Oct 2015-Present

State of Alaska, Division of Senior & Disabilities Services, Provider Certification and Compliance

Senior Services Technician

Feb 2014-Present Nov 2011-Feb 2014

State of Alaska, Division of Senior & Disabilities Services, Quality Assurance

Admin Clerk II

May 2008-Nov 2011

Sue's Tiny Costumes

Office Assistant II

Entrepreneur (currently on hiatus)

Oct 1995-Present

Nine Star Education & Employment

Career Development Mentor & Computer Instructor

Apr 2006-Apr 2008